

□+1 (734) 496-1803 | ☑ jwnchung@umich.edu | ♂ jaewonchung.me | ☑ jaywonchung | ் jae-won-chung-cs

Summary .

I am a third year PhD candidate in CSE at the University of Michigan, working with Professor Mosharaf Chowdhury. I build efficient software systems for deep learning, with a recent focus on the efficient management of not only time, but also energy. I lead the ML Energy initiative.

Education

University of Michigan

Ph.D. candidate in Computer Science and Engineering

University of Michigan

M.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

Seoul National University

B.S. IN ELECTRICAL AND COMPUTER ENGINEERING

- GPA: 4.04/4.3 (overall) 4.15/4.3 (major), Summa Cum Laude
- · Period includes two years of military service.

Publications

- Perseus: Removing Energy Bloat from Large Model Training, <u>Jae-Won Chung</u>, Yile Gu, Insu Jang, Luoxi Meng, Nikhil Bansal, Mosharaf Chowdhury, Preprint, 2023
- Chasing Low-Carbon Electricity for Practical and Sustainable DNN Training, Zhenning Yang, Luoxi Meng, <u>Jae-Won Chung</u>, Mosharaf Chowdhury, ICLR Workshop: Tackling Climate Change with Machine Learning, 2023
- Zeus: Understanding and Optimizing GPU Energy Consumption of DNN Training, Jie You*, <u>Jae-Won Chung</u>*, Mosharaf Chowdhury, Symposium on Networked Systems Design and Implementation (NSDI), 2023 (Acceptance rate = 18.38%)
- ShadowTutor: Distributed Partial Distillation for Mobile Video DNN Inference, <u>Jae-Won Chung</u>, Jae-Yun Kim, Soo-Mook Moon, International Conference on Parallel Processing (ICPP), 2020 (Acceptance rate = 28.99%)

Experience

Energy-Efficient Systems for Machine Learning

SymbioticLab, UMich Sep 2022 - Present

Ann Arbor, MI, USA

Ann Arbor, MI, USA

Sep 2021 - Apr 2023

Seoul, South Korea

Mar 2015 - Aug 2021

Sep 2021 - present

Advisor: Mosharaf Chowdhury

- Zeus: Discovered the trade-off between DNN training time and energy. Designed a Multi-Armed Bandit solution for time-energy optimization.
- · Perseus: A system for energy-efficient large model training. Cuts up to 30% energy without slowdown.
- ML.ENERGY Leaderboard & Colosseum: The first systematic benchmark and interactive comparison service for LLM energy consumption.

Software Systems for Machine Learning

Software Platform Lab, SNU

Advisor: Byung-Gon Chun

Apr 2020 - Jun 2022

• Crane: A GPU cluster manager for AutoML workloads. Built a Kubernetes backend that scaled to 288 GPUs. Contributed core features such as automatic bootstrapping on Docker Swarm and Kubernetes and log streaming through the EFK (Elasticsearch - Fluent Bit - Kibana) stack.

Online Model Specialization for Edge Video DNN Inference

Virtual Machine and Optimization Lab, SNU

ADVISOR: SOO-MOOK MOON

Dec 2019 - Jun 2020

• ShadowTutor: Knowledge distillation from the server to the edge device reduced network data transfer by 95% and increased throughput by 3x.

Few-Shot Learning with Meta-Learning

Computer Vision Lab, SNU

Advisor: Kyoung Mu Lee

Jun 2019 - Dec 2019

Designed improved meta-initialization methods for Model-Agnostic Meta-Learning (MAML) with neural memory modules and convex programs.

Quantitative Susceptibility Mapping with Deep Learning

Lab of Imaging Science and Technology, SNU

Advisor: Jongho Lee

Jun 2019 - Aug 2019

• Designed and implemented a full deep learning pipeline for QSM, a vision task for medical diagnostics with 3D MRI field data, including preprocessing (background removal, phase unwrapping, and patch slicing), augmentation (adding fake calcifications) and modeling (<u>CAD-QSMNet</u>).

JANUARY 11, 2024 JAE-WON CHUNG

^{*} Equal contribution

Open Source Projects

- BERT4Rec-VAE-Pytorch (☆311 ₺ 76), Implementation of BERT4Rec and Netflix VAE recommendation models. PyTorch.
- **Reason** (☆178 🎖 4), A shell for research papers. Rust.
- **Zeus** (2105 214), An energy optimization framework for DNN training. Python and C++.
- Pegasus (☆26 🖁 3), An SSH command runner with a focus on simplicity. Rust.

Number of stars and forks are as of December 26, 2023.

Honors & Awards

Nov 2022 **Carbon Hack '22 Second Best Solution**, <u>Carbon-Aware DNN Training with Zeus</u>, \$25,000

Green Software Foundation

Jul 2021 Kwanjeong Overseas Scholarship, \$100,000 over four years

Kwanjeong Educational Foundation Kwanjeong Educational Foundation

Mar 2019 **Kwanjeong Undergraduate Scholarship,** \$20,000 over two years

Service _____

• Systems/Software Reading Group, Paper reading group inside Michigan CSE, Organizer since Fall 2022

Teaching_

- Operating Systems (SNU, Spring 21), Lead TA, Managed Linux kernel hacking projects and led student team design reviews.
- Computer Architecture (SNU, Fall 20), Peer tutor, Provided 30 hours of online lecture, Best Tutor Award!

Skills ____

Language Python, Rust, CUDA, C++, Verilog, C, Bash **Framework** PyTorch, Pandas, Matplotlib, FastAPI

Methodology Machine Learning, Deep Learning, Multi-Armed Bandit

Tool Docker, Kubernetes, KubeFlow, LaTeX

English TOEFL 120 (Perfect score), GRE 167/170/4.5

JANUARY 11, 2024 JAE-WON CHUNG 2